<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>jennifercooper.ca</title>
    <description>Jennifer Cooper's personal website.</description>
    <link>jennifercooper.ca</link>
    <atom:link href="jennifercooper.ca/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>My Notes on Hiring</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: I am NOT a self-proclaimed hiring expert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are my notes so far on hiring. This list will likely change as I acquire knowledge and feedback from others, so feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:cooper.jennl@gmail.com&quot;&gt;reach out&lt;/a&gt; if you&amp;rsquo;d like to discuss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hiring in the tech industry is one of those tricky things that I&amp;rsquo;ll likely never fully understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the WHY: People are messy and complicated.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My belief is that technical skill is important, but the following are WAY more important. Smart, passionate people can learn technology when given the chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;1. Hire for empathy&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone is different, but we often relate to each other based on our experiences. People who&amp;rsquo;ve had similar experiences in life are often more comfortable with each other. However, most of the time, there can be a fair chasm between what any two people have been through in their lives. In my experience, empathetic people are more capable of conceptualizing another person&amp;rsquo;s point of view, even if it differs drastically from their own. They&amp;rsquo;re able to question their own opinions, or in the least understand how another person could conceivable entertain a different viewpoint. This type of dynamic is hugely important in a team setting where open and constructive dialogue is necessary for growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;2. Watch out for feigned empathy&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some pretty excellent actors out there. Trying to discern whether a person is legitimately empathetic or whether there&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;something else&amp;rsquo; happening can be really difficult. People often reveal themselves within the first month or two of work. This is why it often pays to start people off with a month-long contract&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;3. Try a month (or some finite duration of time)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is something we did at BigMama, and it worked very well. People who weren&amp;rsquo;t a good fit for the company had often moved on by the time a month came around. People who were a good fit stayed. This works well for developers because it gives them a chance to chill out and do their work in a real work setting, as opposed to an interview setting. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;4. Hire for humility&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;+1 for a person who is able to legitimately say &amp;lsquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know&amp;rsquo; in an interview. This response often leads to discussion and further revelation. Also, I usually start jumping up and down when I meet someone who&amp;rsquo;s able to discuss their failures. I think this is indicative of the ability to reflect, which leads to learning and growth (YAY).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;5. Evidence of grit/hard stuff&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Has this person done anything hard? Have they suffered with something? Learning what a person finds to be hard is very interesting, and telling. This one gets tricky, and actually requires a fair amount of empathy from the interviewer. What one person finds to be easy, another can find to be incredibly difficult. As an interviewer you need to know how to ask the right questions to allow someone to feel safe enough to mention the hard stuff. Hard stuff shapes who we are and how we respond to stress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;6. Traditional interviews will never work in tech&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless your business requires you to regurgitate redundant algorithms on the fly, please don&amp;rsquo;t ever ask a developer to write a binary search tree or merge sort in an interview. Just don&amp;rsquo;t. It&amp;rsquo;s condescending. My opinion is that people who are able to recall this type of information on the fly are more comfortable with an &amp;lsquo;artificial&amp;rsquo; environment (like school, for example) and may not cope well in a more fluid environment. Sidebar: developers fresh out of a CS degree may cope just fine, but they’ve spent the greater part of their lives in an artificial environment, so I think cutting them a little slack here is probably the right thing to do. OR even better, never ask them to regurgitate!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;7. Evidence of creative outlet&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does this person paint? Is this person excited and passionate about something outside of technology? People with other facets and dimensions have never been a bad thing in my experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 10:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>jennifercooper.ca/2014/04/09/my-notes-on-hiring/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">jennifercooper.ca/2014/04/09/my-notes-on-hiring/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>First Meetup Success!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We had our first &lt;a href=&quot;http://meetup.com/code-coffee-vancouver&quot;&gt;meetup&lt;/a&gt; this past Tuesday! In case you&amp;rsquo;re wondering, it was pretty OKAY! Nobody died, also the wifi held up (yay!). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Meetup Stats:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The day before the meetup, we had 40 people signed up, with a few on the waitlist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By 5pm on the day of, we had 32 people signed up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We had 23 people actually show up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Good Parts:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The turnout was ~55% women!!!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There was enough space for everyone to sit comfortably.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Waves staff were really accomodating.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nobody had to wait long for coffee/treats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The people in attendance were quite pleasant, and gave plenty of constructive feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Not-so-good Parts:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some people wanted to &amp;lsquo;work&amp;rsquo;, while others wanted to &amp;lsquo;discuss&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Those that did want to discuss, had a hard time hearing eachother.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These results lead me to ask a couple questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do we accomodate people who want to discuss, or people who want to work? Or both?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does this venue serve our needs if we want to include people who would like to discuss.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More on this later!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, we got &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.straight.com/life/570441/geek-speak-meredith-underell-vancouver-chapter-lead-ladies-learning-code&quot;&gt;press&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 19:31:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>jennifercooper.ca/2014/01/25/first-meetup-success/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">jennifercooper.ca/2014/01/25/first-meetup-success/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Starting a Meetup</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On a whim, myself and a friend of mine (&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/meredithu&quot;&gt;@MeredithU&lt;/a&gt;) decided to co-organize a Meetup called &lt;a href=&quot;http://meetup.com/code-coffee-vancouver&quot;&gt;Code and Coffee (Vancouver)&lt;/a&gt;.  The idea is to come out once a month for an evening, and work on a personal project that you haven’t had a chance to get to. There are always problems to solve and ways to make the world more efficient. As developers, we all have ideas that we’d love to build, but many of us spend our time building things for other people (read: making a living).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, we wanted the group’s mandate to be “NO ASSHOLES”. But Meredith more eloquently put it as “An upbeat positive attitude and zero tolerance for stereotypes”. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hope is to create a gender neutral group of developers. In order to achieve this, we need to figure out a way to attract an equal ratio of women to men. We think that if we can achieve this goal, gender will become a non-issue during our events. Many other female devs will attest to the how depressing it is to walk into a tech Meetup and be the only woman. It just really, really sucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We chose to have our first Meetup at &lt;a href=&quot;http://wavescoffee.com/howe-howe-smithe&quot;&gt;Waves Coffee House&lt;/a&gt; in downtown Vancouver. When we were first conceptualizing the event, this seemed like the perfect place – relatively cheap, lots of treats, central location, free wifi etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an organizational Meetup noob I didn’t foresee that within a week we would have nearly 130 developers in the group, and a full first meetup – maxed out at 30 people, with 15 on the waitlist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, we were so sure that “only a few people” would be interested that we asked the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Girl-Development&quot;&gt;Girl Development Meetup&lt;/a&gt; organizer (&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/sabaelhilo&quot;&gt;@SabaElHilo&lt;/a&gt;) to send our event out to the Girl Development Meetup group.  So we actually have 30 + 14 (from Girl Dev), and 15 on the waitlist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had originally imagined myself sitting comfortably around a table of 8, sipping a mocha. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily for us, the people at Waves have been wonderfully accommodating. When I dropped the we-have-40-developers-coming-on-Tuesday bomb, the store manager didn’t seem swayed.  In fact, he offered to order us extra treats. Then he dropped the we-have-one-router wifi bomb on me… so, we&amp;rsquo;re just going to see how that goes…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re going to iterate on this. We’re going to collect lots of feedback from our members. We’re going to keep making mistakes and learning from them, with the goal of helping other developers (and ourselves) carve out development time for those ‘silly’ ideas that come to you in the shower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JOIN US: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Code-Coffee-Vancouver/&quot;&gt;http://www.meetup.com/Code-Coffee-Vancouver/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 20:01:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>jennifercooper.ca/2014/01/14/starting-a-meetup/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">jennifercooper.ca/2014/01/14/starting-a-meetup/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello World</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;HELLO WORLD&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally have a blog. Stop bugging me!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2013 20:27:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>jennifercooper.ca/2013/12/10/hello-world/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">jennifercooper.ca/2013/12/10/hello-world/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
